(ETHEREAL MUSIC PLAYING)
BART: I found a song
that saved me through time.
A song that opened my life
up to things
I couldn't have
possibly imagined.
It made me believe that...
That dreams do come true.
(CROWD CHEERING)
I dreamed of something good
with my dad before he died,
of being a good husband,
a good father,
of writing songs that could
touch the hearts of millions
with the same hope
that music gave to me.
And it all came true.
But what comes next
when you've gotten
all your dreams?
After all
the applause dies down
and the crowds go home,
is there life
after the happily-ever-after?
When it all gets hard again,
when the pain never seems
to go away?
What do you do
when the only thing
in the whole world
you have to hold on to
is a song?
(UPLIFTING MUSIC PLAYING)
SHANNON: Hey, Bart,
the bus is here.
I just got Gracie down
for a nap.
-(SHUSHING)
-You about ready
to leave or no?
SHANNON: (SOFTLY) Ah.
BART: Well, dang.
Bummer. I mean,
I was really hoping
to see Sam before I left.
SHANNON: I wonder where he is.
I was gonna let him borrow
my Nano.
Loaded up some sweet new U2,
-some Jars...
-Whoa.
...big band.
-(TUTS AND SIGHS)
-Oh, well.
Too bad he's not here.
Yes,
that is too bad.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Hey, big man.
You wanna talk about it?
Why do you always miss
the good stuff?
-(CHUCKLES UNCOMFORTABLY)
-SHANNON: Buddy,
your dad's out
working for us, Sam.
But yeah, I'll miss him, too.
I'll be back in two days,
okay?
And then you and me,
maybe we could... Oh.
What should we listen to?
Here, you pick.
(BUTTON CLICKS)
(I CAN ONLY IMAGINE
BY MERCYME PLAYING)
MAN ON RADIO:
I Can Only Imagine by MercyMe,
one of the most beloved songs
of all time
shows no signs
of slowing down.
WOMAN ON RADIO:
As MercyMe's surprise hit
I Can Only Imagine
shook the world
and went double platinum.
MAN 2 ON RADIO: Here it is,
by popular demand,
the song that everyone is
talking about,
coming in this week
at number one.
WOMAN 2:
...I Can Only Imagine.
WOMAN 3: This group reached
number four
on the Adult
Contemporary radio charts
and soared to number one
in Christian Radio.
Here's MercyMe.
All right.
ANNOUNCER: It's such an honor
to announce the nominees
for the best
Christian Artist of the year.
You boys better have
that money ready.
If we win, I'm doin' it.
What exactly are we doing,
Bartholomew?
(CHUCKLES) He's gotta use
whatever we write
in his speech.
And he can't look at it
till he gets on stage.
I'm so not comfortable
with this.
ALL: Shut up, Robby.
Oh, man, I hope we lose.
And the winner is
MercyMe
for I Can Only Imagine! Woo!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
♪ Will I dance for You, Jesus
♪ Or in awe of You
be still? ♪
BART: Who am I kiddin'?
I'm just a kid
from Greenville, Texas,
you know.
(CHUCKLING) I...
My meemaw used to say to me,
she'd say, "Pickles..."
(MEN LAUGHING FAINTLY)
Pickles was
her nickname for me.
-(AUDIENCE LAUGHS FAINTLY)
-BART: It's very endearing.
Um, and she would say
"Sometimes, happily-ever-afters
do come true."
But then she'd say,
"Don't bet on it.
Get a real job."
-You know? So...
-(AUDIENCE CHUCKLING)
Um...
Meemaw, God is good.
Dreams do come true.
Thank you so much, everyone.
Have a great night.
(ALL CHEERING)
All right. Easy money, boys.
Easy money.
Ah, thank you.
-(PHONE VIBRATING)
-BART: Ooh.
-Hey.
-SHANNON: Hi, I just thought
-I'd check in on ya.
-We won.
SHANNON: Again? (LAUGHING)
I'm so proud of you guys!
-Babe! That's awesome.
-Yeah, we're gonna have
to take another box
of these things to storage
if we keep winning.
I'm glad one of us is winning.
Sounds like World War III.
-That would somehow be easier.
-(KIDS YELLING)
Hey, I know Sam wanted
to talk to you.
Sam, you wanna talk to Daddy?
Here you go.
-Hey, Dad.
-Hey, Sam.
How's the party going?
Are you having fun, big man?
I barfed.
Is that right? Um...
I won the costume contest.
Oh, that's great, bud.
Ah, man, I bet
you were a great Legolas.
Um, the bow and arrow,
how's your aim?
I shot the white lamp
and it broke
so Mommy took it away.
I never cared for that lamp.
SHANNON: All right, Sam.
Say bye to Daddy.
SAM: Bye, Daddy. I love you.
I love you too, big man.
Hi. I'm back.
I'm outta gas, man.
BART: Hang in there, Shannon.
Just another tour,
couple more albums
and we're gonna be set.
You know, I think
that's what you said
last tour.
Yeah, that's fair. Um...
And great. Someone gave
Sam back his bow and arrow.
I gotta go. Love you, Millard.
You too, M...
(HOPEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(RADIO STATIC BUZZING)
ARTHUR: I want you
to go chase your dream.
(INAUDIBLE)
And I want you to catch it.
BART: I promise.
I caught my dream, Dad.
I miss you.
(PHONE VIBRATING)
Hey, babe.
SHANNON:
(VOICE SHAKING) Bart?
-Shannon, what's going on?
-I can't get Sam to wake up.
-What?
-I can't get Sam to wake up!
WOMAN: Hey, baby, Mommy
and Daddy are here, okay?
-NURSE: Coming through.
-We're all right here for you.
You just need to keep
breathing for me, okay?
Everything is gonna be okay.
You're okay.
No, no, I've gotta...
Okay.
Hi.
-Hey!
-I'm here, baby.
(CRYING SOFTLY)
BART: I'm here.
What, um...
(SHANNON CRYING)
What happened?
He had a, a seizure,
(SIGHS) or something,
and now they can't get him
to wake up. (SNIFFLES)
I don't really know.
(SIGHS) Bart, I'm scared.
-(SNIFFLES)
-I know, I know.
Me too.
WOMAN ON PA:
Paging Dr. Lund, line 3.
Dr. Lund, line 3.
SAM: Mama, I'm thirsty.
Hi!
Baby!
Baby, hi!
BART: Right. So we just
lower his sugar intake,
and then what?
He's got to lose some weight
or something, right?
No. Once again,
that is Type 2 diabetes.
Your son has Type 1.
This insulin is life support.
Sam's glucose was 840.
That's 10 times
the normal range.
There's another kid here
that's slightly higher
than him
that we haven't been able
to stabilize yet.
And if you would have
gotten him here any later,
Sam would have been
in the exact same position.
I wish
it could be different,
but this is Sam's life now.
It's yours, too.
(BART INHALES
AND EXHALES DEEPLY)
SAM: Do we have to, Daddy?
(LANCET CLICKS)
BURT: (SIGHS) Yeah, buddy.
Um...
I'm afraid we do.
I need your finger, okay?
SAM: Okay.
-(LANCET CLICKS)
-BART: Okay, bud.
SAM: Wait, wait, wait.
What do you do
when you're scared?
(INHALES AND EXHALE SHARPLY)
I think everything's
a little less scary
with a friend, right?
Watch me.
(LANCET CLICKS)
That's not so bad.
Okay?
It just stings a little bit.
You wanna pick out a song?
Okay.
Pick a good one.
(INHALES)
(40 BY U2 PLAYING)
Good choice.
Okay, buddy.
-(LANCET CLICKS)
-(WINCES)
Hey, hey, it's okay.
-It's okay. It's okay.
-Good job.
(SIGHS)
(GLUCOSE METER BEEPS)
All right, buddy.
-(SAM WINCES)
-SHANNON: Yep. You're okay.
-BART: Okay.
-(SAM CRYING)
-You're hurting me.
-SHANNON: It's okay.
-Daddy's just trying to help.
-(TABLE THUDS LOUDLY)
BART: Get away from me!
I don't have my phone. I think
I left my phone in the...
In the car.
I gotta... I think it's here.
♪ To sing this song?
♪ How long
♪ How long?
♪ How long? ♪
(MUSIC FADES)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
I'm so sorry.
(WOMAN CRYING)
(MUTTERING) No, no, no.
(CRIES SOFTLY)
ARTHUR: You're not
good enough, Bart.
Dreams don't pay the bills.
Nothing good comes from it.
All it does...
is keep you from all this.
From knowing what's real.
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
-ARTHUR: Wake up!
-GRACIE: Dad, Charlie took
-my Game Boy!
-BART: Give her back
-her Game Boy.
-GRACIE: Give it back!
(INHALES AND EXHALES DEEPLY)
(CHARLIE CHUCKLES)
BART: Hey, Mom's home!
CHARLIE: Mom!
GRACIE: Mom!
(CHARLIE SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
GRACIE: Give it back!
So when were you guys planning
on cleaning up?
It looks like a neutron bomb
went off in here.
All right, everybody.
Come on, guys.
Clean up duty right now.
Let's go.
-Come on. Come on.
-Miles.
You're Donald Ducking it
again, bro.
-MILES: What's that?
-Wear your pants.
Can you go find
some pants, please?
-SHANNON: Gracie could you...
-Okay.
SHANNON: ...please help Miles
find some pants?
-You got it, Mom. Miles.
-Thank you.
Charlie, clean up duty. Now.
CHARLIE: All over it, Mom.
-(MILES GIGGLES)
-(DOOR CLOSES)
SHANNON: Ah,
back in the old flower chair.
Must have been a hard day.
Any luck writing?
BART: I got nothing.
How was your counseling thing?
Good. Lonely, but good.
You're welcome
to step in anytime.
I think
it's really helping me,
and I thought you might...
I know, I know.
This is the part
where you tell me
touring is the only therapy
you'll ever need.
I hope you're right.
(BART SIGHS)
How is he?
He hasn't been out of his room.
He's late. Again.
By about 37 minutes.
GRACIE: Mom, Miles needs you.
(SHANNON SIGHS,
CLEARS THROAT)
Why don't you let me
handle Sam
and you help the...
MAN ON LAPTOP:
And so the thing
that I really love
while playing ukulele
is trying...
Just keep playing it
like that, right?
And then take something away.
And then... Oh.
There's
a surprise right there, right?
If you like what you're
watching and you're...
BART: Hey, man.
(SAM PLAYING UKULELE)
Sam.
Can you hear me?
Sorry, what?
You were supposed
to check your blood sugar,
like, 40 minutes ago.
You got time for your music,
so make time for your insulin.
All right?
Oh, sorry. Yeah, I just
kind of got carried away.
Okay.
Well, how about now?
Yeah. Sorry.
(GLUCOSE METER BEEPS)
See, Sam,
this is why we do this.
You're low.
Come on, eat.
I'm not hungry.
(SIGHS) Come on, Sam.
I'm not doing this again.
You know what this is, son.
-This is life support.
-Life support.
No, I heard you the first
300 times that you said it.
SHANNON: Sam.
Hey, look at me.
You said you wanted
to handle this on your own
and this is
what that looks like.
Your dad and I can't be here
every time...
Okay. Do you think
I like grounding you?
Do you think I like
taking your phone away?
Fine.
Sammy, where are you going?
I don't know. Ask him.
He probably has
my whole life mapped out
-on those charts.
-(PHONE VIBRATING)
It's Brick. I gotta take this.
Brick, talk to me.
Yep. Yep. On my way.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
No.
(GROANS)
-(WATER RUNNING)
-(HUMMING TUNE)
HILARY: I miss Mayberry
♪ Sitting on the porch
♪ Drinking
ice-cold Cherry Coke
♪ Where everything is
black and white ♪
(VOCALIZING)
(SCREAMING)
-(SHIVERING) Ooh.
-(CHUCKLES)
(GROANING) Oh,
I will get you, Tim.
(GASPS)
That was like,
right at my head.
-Mmm-hmm.
-I can't feel my face.
What?
I got the tour.
Babe! That's incredible.
-(CHUCKLES)
-(CHUCKLING) Congrats.
Ah, honey, you've worked
so hard for this.
-TIM: Mmm-hmm.
-(INHALES AND EXHALES DEEPLY)
Come here.
Oh. I'm so proud of you.
When you least expect it,
Tim Timmons!
(GRUMBLES)
(EXHALES)
-TIM: Oh, hey.
-Hey.
Um...
I'm sorry it's not more money.
Don't do that.
This tour is your dream.
It's our dream.
Okay? I'll pick up
extra shifts.
-It'll be fine.
-Okay.
You would do the same for me.
Don't.
Okay. Bye.
Hey, whoa.
I know that. What is that?
No, it...
(INHALES)
It's nothing. (CLEARS THROAT)
You have a big day.
Go! Shoo!
Ah. I know what this is.
-I know what this means.
-No. Do you?
You're ready.
Yeah. You're ready. Come on.
-Give me your wrist.
-Yeah, no.
-You sure?
-No, no, no.
Still a work in progress
over here, bud.
-Okay.
-Ask me again tomorrow.
It's kinda cute
to tell you no.
-Is it?
-Mmm-hmm.
-For now, you keep...
...your weird rituals
to yourself.
And you keep
this stethoscope thingy handy
for later.
-Weirdo.
-Mmm-hmm.
What does that even mean?
I don't know.
You're gonna find out.
Hey! No, actually, really.
-What...
-Stop talking.
Got it. Okay.
You took it too far, Timmons.
Two guitars bagged...
You're ready. Ready.
(HEALING BEGINS BY
TENTH AVENUE NORTH PLAYING)
♪ Afraid to let
your secrets out
♪ Everything that you hide
♪ Comes crashing
through the door now ♪
BRICK: Gentlemen,
with a heavy heart,
Jim is cashin' in.
He wants to spend more time
with his family.
And apparently,
Audio Adrenaline is
calling it quits, too
because Mark's voice can't
take the abuse anymore.
-So...
-(SIGHS)
...it seems we find ourselves
at the crossroads.
One band member down
and no headliner.
So where does that leave us?
We're alone.
Utterly alone.
Well, that was what you call
a rhetorical question, Nathan,
but thank you.
Now the silver linin' here is
that now you boys are
the headliner.
(CHUCKLES)
Imagine has had
more lives than a stray cat.
But record sales have not
exactly been stellar
as of late.
And we haven't had
a hit single
in quite a while now.
So the question is
are we headliner material?
And I am open
to any new ideas, fellas.
MIKE: He's talking
about you, Bart.
You got another hit cookin'?
It'd be good timing.
He's got nothin'.
You don't have anything?
-He's got nothing.
-Very helpful, Mike.
-Thank you.
-Yep.
Um, if we're headlining,
who's the opening act?
Hi. Um...
I don't know
who needs to hear this,
but I think, uh,
your bus is on fire.
-(GASPS) Oh, no.
-No, I'm kidding.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY) I'm kidding.
Um, but I did hear
that that happened once.
It was the incense.
It helps me unwind.
I am sorry about that.
Boys, this is Tim Timmons.
He's your opening act.
-Tim, MercyMe.
-TIM: Wow, guys.
It is so good for you
to meet me.
Okay. That's new.
Are there any snacks?
(CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
-Thank you so much.
-Pick out your bunk, bro.
-Hey, great.
-Yeah.
-I'm gonna be back for that.
-Okay.
Life of the party.
Oh, he's a barrel
full of monkeys, isn't he?
I'm not sure I like him.
Well, the folks
at the homeless shelter
he works with seem to.
Of course he works
with a homeless shelter.
BRICK: He also has
your sense of humor,
which I find disquieting.
(BART SIGHS)
I know that look, Brick.
What's up, man?
Shannon called me.
She's worried.
So am I. I mean,
I'm not sure this whole
duct-taped-together tour
thing's gonna work anyhow.
Maybe you stay home
for a while,
writing or something,
you know.
Your family needs you,
Shannon needs you.
Sam, especially.
I don't know, man.
It's just... It's hard.
Why's it got to be so hard?
Which part?
All of it.
Come on, man.
You got your dream.
You inspired
millions of people.
I mean, what did you think
was gonna happen?
You're just gonna ride off
into the sunset?
No more struggles or pain?
Good Lord never
promised us that, man.
That's not
how this thing works.
Look, I need this tour, Scott.
It's the only place I feel
like I can breathe again, man.
Stuff's falling apart at home.
Tour will give me
the space to figure it out.
I need this.
I don't think you know
what you need right now.
(BART SIGHS)
Okay.
If we're gonna do this,
we're gonna take
that guitarist from Audio A,
what's his name? Barry.
Because we're gonna need
some big guns
now that Jim's gone.
I think that's great, man.
No objections here.
And then Sam.
Sam needs a father right now.
What is that supposed to mean?
I...
I don't mean nothin' by it.
-It's just, you know...
-I'm a great dad, Scott.
Yeah, I know. I'm just saying.
We'll bring him with us.
-Come again?
-No, no, no. Sorry.
That's... That's stupid.
That's actually not
a bad idea, Bartholomew.
Brick, that's not
what I meant.
-What I'm saying is...
-Yes, sir.
We're gonna take
that kid with us.
There's no way
Shannon says yes to that.
Yeah, sure.
Why not?
Wait. You're...
You're okay with Sam...
-With Sam going?
-SHANNON: Yeah.
I'm ready for a change.
Besides, I think it'll be good
for the both of you.
(HOPEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(BRICK CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(NATHAN LAUGHING)
BRICK: All right,
you knuckleheads.
Wheels up in five minutes.
Let's go.
-(SHANNON SIGHS)
-SAM: Yeah, it is, it is.
Put your finger right there.
-Okay.
-That's a C chord.
Yeah? And then if you put
one there on this string...
I'm worried I might break him.
SAM: ...and that last string...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Like that.
Or he just might fix you.
-Hey, guys.
-ALL: Hey, Barry!
BARRY: Greetings!
-I'm here. I'm here.
-NATHAN: What's up, man?
Welcome to the party.
-How are you?
-Robby! Hey, man.
-Good to see you.
-Can you take that for me?
MIKE: What's up, man?
Fast mover.
BART: Hey. One minute.
SAM: All right, guys.
-BART: Let's go.
-Got you. Okay. Goonies,
never say die.
And don't burn
the house down, all right?
BRICK: All right,
that's enough.
Move it or lose it, ladies.
Let's go.
The last dibs on bunks,
I guess.
-You ready?
-Yeah.
BART: Let's go.
(AIR BRAKE HISSING)
(EXHALES)
-(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
-(PHONE CHIMES)
WOMAN ON PHONE: Well done.
You're sounding great.
-Let's try that again.
-(SOFT RATTLING)
-(RATTLING STOPS)
-(SAM CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(ACOUSTIC GUITAR PLAYING)
That's sick, man.
Is that open D? (CHUCKLES)
It is.
Do you, um...
Do you play?
A little. Yeah.
Nice. Is your dad teaching
you how?
Uh, myself mostly.
Yeah.
Dad's got a lot going on
with the band.
Hey, so, um,
what's your job here,
like, in the circus?
I don't have a job.
I'm just kinda...
I mean, I'm a rookie.
This is my first tour, so.
(EXHALES)
It's my first tour, too.
-(SOFTLY) Rock on.
-(CHUCKLES)
Yep.
Yo, so, um,
feel free to say no,
like, if it's not your thing,
but would you maybe want
to guitar tech for me?
Just keep them tuned up
in their cases,
ready to rock
at a moment's notice.
I can't pay you for it, but...
No, I'm in. I mean...
I mean... I...
I mean, I love that.
I'd love to if... Yeah.
Killer, bro.
Hey, guys!
First-time busser here.
And probably a stupid question
but can you use the bathroom
while the bus is moving?
Yeah, of course.
Knock yourself out.
Who's the rookie now?
Job one.
Keep it safe.
-(UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYING)
-All right, let's go.
Let's go.
MIKE: Bart, he's in.
Let's do it!
I've got too much to do, man.
It's stupid anyway.
Like, you invented this.
Cool. When did
accountant Bart show up?
(SIGHS) I don't know, man.
About the time I invited
my diabetic kid along
on this writer's-block-inducing,
first-time-headlining,
make-or-break tour.
What's the worst
that could happen, Michael?
Wow. Okay,
you just let me know
when real Bart shows back up.
-He'll be missed.
-Yeah, I miss him too. Thanks.
Let's do it. Brick, buckle up.
TIM: Mmm. (TSKS)
(EXHALES)
You have surfed
20-foot waves in Kaua'i,
climbed Half Dome,
survived the eighth grade,
twice.
You can do this.
All right. Ready?
On my count. Three,
two,
one.
-(BREAKS SCREECHING)
-(TIM EXCLAIMS)
-(THUDDING)
-TIM: (GROANING) Oh!
-Come on!
-(ALL LAUGHING)
NATHAN: Dude.
TIM: All right.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Yeah.
You're all dead to me.
(ALL LAUGHING)
-Give me a hug.
-NATHAN: No! No! No!
MIKE: No, no, no, hug.
-MIKE: Is that water?
-(NATHAN SCREAMING)
MIKE: Is that water, dude?
ROBBY: We heard that.
TIM: I used your toothbrush.
I'm gonna get pink eye, right?
(CREED BY
RICH MULLINS PLAYING)
♪ I believe
in God the Father
♪ Almighty Maker of Heaven
and Maker of Earth
♪ And in Jesus Christ
♪ His only begotten Son
our Lord... ♪
You know, that's how Nathan
nearly burned
the bus down, right?
Mama didn't raise no fool.
(BOTTLE SHAKING)
-BART: Must be riveting.
-(FRIDGE DOOR CLOSES)
TIM: It is.
It's The Origin of Hymns.
I've always been obsessed
with It Is Well With My Soul.
BART: I love that one.
It's one of the hardest
redemption stories
I've ever heard which led
to one of the greatest hymns
of all time.
I'd love to write a song
like that someday.
(BART EXHALES)
Me, too.
(CHUCKLES)
You did, man.
-Maybe another one.
-Yeah.
Yeah. I'd love
to get on the board someday.
I got this one song
that's like stuck in my head.
Knock yourself out, bro.
Um, I don't really...
do junk food.
(PUKING)
-(TOILET FLUSHING)
-(GROANS)
(COUGHING)
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and gentlemen,
-please welcome Tim Timmons.
-(PEOPLE CHEERING)
If I don't make it,
tell my story.
-SAM: Okay.
-Okay.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
Oh, wow. They sure do
build them taller in Dallas.
Okay.
Here we go.
(FINALLY BREATHING
BY TIM TIMMONS PLAYING)
♪ If all I do is just believe
♪ I'll miss the forest
for the trees
♪ Your love moves me
to my feet
♪ It's like
I'm finally breathing ♪
BART: Hey, Mr. Guitar Tech.
Did you check your level?
I will. Okay?
Hey, man, I'm not gonna
hunt you down on this.
It's your responsibility now.
Yeah, I got it, boss.
♪ I'm finally breathing
(CROWD CHEERING)
(BEAUTIFUL BY MERCYME PLAYING)
♪ You're beautiful
♪ You are made
for so much more
♪ Than all of this
♪ You're beautiful ♪
TIM: So clean.
I mean, Barry is a beast.
SAM: He's all right.
(SCOFFS) Yeah. I...
I mean, you're like,
if your dad can learn
how to sing, right?
Bro,
five middle-aged white dudes
just melted like,
a thousand people's faces off.
But, I mean, we totally did
all the heavy lifting.
♪ You are treasured
♪ You are sacred
You are His
♪ You're beautiful ♪
Thank you, Dallas! Good night!
BRICK: Timmons.
You know, I still can't
figure out these arrows.
I mean, which way is catering?
It's...
Your set sucks.
Wow. Okay.
Just don't be boring.
Give us some pizzazz
and panache, you know?
Your job's to get
the crowd stoked,
get 'em amped up.
I'm like, one dude out on stage
with an acoustic guitar, man.
Sounds like excuses, Tim.
Look, if you're gonna
be a bear,
be a grizzly.
Hey, try not to sugarcoat it
next time, you know.
-BRICK: Whatever. Love you.
-Love you too.
(SIGHS)
(ACOUSTIC GUITAR PLAYING)
TIM: Dude!
-Oh, Tim. I'm sorry.
-No, no. Dude, dude, dude!
-SAM: No, no, I...
-No, no, no.
-I took it without asking you.
-Don't freak out.
-It's not right. I'm sorry...
-I just...
-Shut up!
I want you in my band.
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome Tim Timmons!
Okay, bud. Get your ears on.
(CROWD CHEERING)
TIM: Hey there, Birmingham.
BARRY: What you got?
MIKE: Okay. I got all reds...
-Barry.
-NATHAN: Let's go. I got you.
-(MUFFLED DRUMMING)
-MIKE: I don't know
-if that'll help me.
-Is that drums?
What, you...
Go.
Come on!
One, two, one, two, three!
Whoo!
Yeah!
My main man, Sam,
bringin' the noise!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(TIM PLAYING ACOUSTIC GUITAR)
♪ I need you
♪ Oh, I need you
♪ I need you ♪
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Go on, have a seat.
Go on, now. Have a seat.
Have a seat.
I've been workin'
on a new song.
(CROWD CHEERING SOFTLY)
TIM: It's not ready yet.
-(CROWD GROANS)
-Soon. Soon, soon.
This is where
I'm living right now.
About 150 years ago,
a prominent lawyer
from Chicago
named Horatio Spafford
put his entire fortune
into real estate.
And not long after,
the great Chicago fires
happened,
and poof,
everything he worked
so hard for his entire life
was just gone.
So he puts his wife
and their four sweet daughters
on a boat to Europe
to get 'em out of the city
so he can rebuild.
And on that fateful voyage,
a freighter hits them.
All four of his daughters
drowned in the crash,
and only his wife survives.
Now, I want you
to stop and think
how you'd respond
to having
nearly everything in your life
taken from you,
just... in an instant.
This man...
jumps on another boat
to go be with his grieving wife,
and as the captain
of the vessel tells them
that they are over
the exact spot
where his daughters died,
what do you think he did?
Did he wave his fist
up in the air at God?
Did he just
lay down? Give up?
Both of those responses
would have been understandable,
right?
But no.
Instead,
he takes out a pen and paper
and proceeds to write
one of the most beautiful songs
in the history of the world,
It Is Well with My Soul.
(CROWD CHEERING)
TIM: Yeah.
Yeah.
It reminds me of the words
in the Book of Daniel
in the Bible
when the three Israelites are
facing the fiery furnace
and their imminent death.
In all of the terror
and fear and...
not even understanding
why this is happening to them,
all they could say
to that twisted king's face was
"Our God is able to deliver us."
"But even if he doesn't...
"Even if he doesn't,
"our hope
"is in God alone.
"Nothing you can do to us
"will ever take that away."
So,
whatever you're going through,
I don't care
if it's divorce, cancer,
depression,
you're failing algebra,
all of the fires,
storms,
the pain, the trauma...
(SNIFFLES, EXHALES)
You're never alone.
(CROWD CHEERING)
You are never alone.
-There you go.
-SHANNON: Oh, Thank you.
Counting the days
till your guy is back, too?
(INHALES) Yep. (CHUCKLES)
Does it ever get easier?
Clumsy, messy maybe,
but, no, not easy.
-Well, I...
-Mom, whatever Sophie's
about to say is a lie.
-(CHUCKLES)
-SOPHIE: Mom.
-What, baby?
-Charlie tried
-to drown me.
-(PHONE VIBRATING)
(AUTOMATED MESSAGE)
This is Shannon.
Leave your message
at the beep. Beep. (CHUCKLES)
Hey, it's me. Uh...
I guess you're probably busy
with the kids.
I just, uh,
thought I'd check in
on you guys.
Sam's keeping up
with his medicine pretty good.
Sorry. How late are we?
BART: Well, to be honest,
I'm keeping up with his meds.
It's a full-time job
but we're making it work.
(EVERYWHERE I GO
BY TIM TIMMONS PLAYING)
♪ There's a city
that calls me by name
♪ Yes, as I run this race
♪ I am cheered by the saints
♪ There's a city
that calls me by name
♪ There's a future
that runs... ♪
BART: The tour is...
Is going surprisingly smooth
under the circumstances.
♪ ...through my veins
♪ And there's
nothing on Earth
♪ That can stand
in the way...
BART: There's
a songwriter story,
Horatio Spafford,
that Tim won't
stop talking about.
♪ Hey! Everywhere I go
on this road, high and low ♪
BART: Oh, and Brickell
may have lost his mind.
I am here with Scott Brickell,
manager of some amazing acts
like Audio Adrenaline
and MercyMe
to discuss his new book,
The Business Behind the Song.
"Tips and tricks
for navigating
"a successful career
"in the ever expanding
modern music industry."
Wow, that's a mouthful,
but obviously...
BART: So, yes, Scott Brickell
wrote a book...
(CHUCKLING) I guess.
He said that...
(MIMICS BRICK) "One of us
has to write around here."
INTERVIEWER: So, tell me,
why'd you wanna
-write this book?
-(EXHALES)
I mean...
Why...
Why does a grizzly
slaughter an elk?
Or...
Why does a fox gnaw
his foot off
when he's caught in a trap?
Oh, he's bombing. This is bad.
Oh, it's not bad.
It's catastrophic.
I think he's crushing it.
(CRUNCHES)
BART: No, Nathan,
he's not crushing. No.
Sam!
(LAUGHING) I'm sorry.
BART: I almost hate
to say it but...
I think Sam is
built for the road.
Yeah, he's actually playin'
on stage with Tim Timmons.
He's totally in his element.
It's awesome to watch.
And he and Tim kicked off
our confetti cannon.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
If you're gonna be a bear,
am I right?
BART: It's a...
Yeah, um...
A long story. Um...
Love you, Millard.
TIM: Hot dog.
Whoever does it faster
gets it.
Truth is, Shannon,
I got no clue what I'm doing.
♪ ...with You
♪ Where I go, I go with
♪ You ♪
(CHUCKLES) I know. It's like,
imagine just a whole wall
full of all of that.
One more time
and I will cut you.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
TIM: I've got this chorus
stuck in my head.
About ready to give up on it.
What's up with tracing
over your tattoo?
Oh.
It's not a tattoo.
I draw it fresh.
Well then,
why not get it tatted? I mean,
save some ink.
That would miss the point
which is
me telling God
and reminding myself
that I'm grateful.
Thank you for another day.
You know, I overheard
you and my dad
talking about that book
and then,
you know, that song that
you talked about on stage...
TIM: Mmm-hmm.
...I don't have
what that guy had but...
-I wish I did.
-Yeah?
What if you could?
(THE HURT AND THE HEALER
BY MERCYME PLAYING)
♪ Fall into your arms
♪ Open wide
♪ When the hurt and the healer
♪ Collide ♪
(TOILET FLUSHING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(SIGHS)
(HOPEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(HOPEFUL MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
BRICK: And there's old,
useless Timmons.
Sticks and stones, Brickell.
I felt that.
Hey, do not say anything.
Do not say anything.
Do not say...
Hey, that looks
ridiculously heavy.
Uh, I think it's time
for you to check your level.
SAM: Yeah, I'll get to it.
I'm happy to take over.
I can help you with that.
I said I'm fine, okay?
-I'm taking care of it.
-Okay.
Cool. Awesome.
Good talk. Cool. Great.
Dad of the year. Ooh.
You're the top dad. Awesome.
(BREATH TREMBLING)
(TREMBLING)
(SNIFFLES)
BART: No. Sam! Sam!
Sam.
-Bart, what's...
-Get him up.
-Let me just hold him up.
-Somebody call 911.
-MIKE: What happened?
-Sam?
Hey, buddy.
You're gonna be okay.
It'll be okay. It's okay.
Just hold him.
Okay.
It's okay, Sam. It's okay.
-Breathe. Just breathe.
-You're okay, buddy.
It's on me, Shannon.
I'm so sorry. I just...
It's not your fault.
You didn't do this to Sam.
He was my responsibility.
I took him on tour with me.
Who else is there to blame?
(TAPPING ON DOOR)
DOCTOR: He's resting now.
You guys can come back.
(SHANNON SIGHS)
(SHANNON CRIES SOFTLY)
Is he enjoying himself
at least?
Bet you guys are
feeling great out there.
Honestly, I'm having trouble
feeling anything right now.
This is about more than Sam.
I mean, no one taught me
how to...
How to be a dad.
I got no freaking clue,
Shannon.
Mine died right when
he was getting good at it.
Now, Sam...
I think God gave our kid
the wrong dad.
Like, I'm the wrong one.
(SIGHS) Millard,
you're the only one.
You're his father.
You don't
have to get it perfect.
Just be there for him.
I pray for you.
A lot.
Always have.
I'm here.
And so is the Jesus
you sing about every night.
He's in it all
with you. (SIGHS)
And he didn't make a mistake.
Sam's all the best parts
of you. (SNIFFLES)
So, just fight.
Please fight.
Fight for our son.
You know, sometimes we think
our story is over...
but it's only the beginning.
(TIM CHUCKLES)
(HILARY CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Just...
What is this?
Surprise!
What?
Wow.
Yeah. Wow.
(TIM CHUCKLES)
Oh, wow.
When you least expect it,
Tim Timmons.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey, bud.
Hey.
Mom said you're thinking
about not letting me finish
the tour.
Yeah, man, I think, um...
I think you're safer
here at home.
On a schedule.
Dad, I...
I think I wanna do music.
I mean, I get around you guys
and Tim and it's like...
It calls to me like a dream.
Dreams don't...
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Man. Wow. Um...
I wanna support you, son.
I do.
But until you can learn
to take care of yourself,
I just gotta focus on
keeping you breathing.
So, no.
You're not gonna finish.
Then I'll get my dreams
without you.
You did it without your dad.
I guess I can do it, too.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
TIM: Let me guess.
You didn't hit the lotto.
You wanna talk about it?
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, me neither.
You know, I'm actually...
I'm glad you're here.
I got a favor to ask.
BART: I got a lot going on
right now, man.
I need you to finish this
for me.
It's really personal
like Imagine.
And I just... I got stuck.
(BART SCOFFS)
(TIM PLAYS SOFT TUNE
ON PIANO)
I think you might be
living this right now.
I don't think you have a clue
what I'm living right now.
Look, I don't have your voice
and I don't care
if anybody knows it was me.
I just wanna write something
that helps people.
That's really all I want
anymore these days.
Like, this song
needs you, man.
It needs Horatio's soul.
I really think
you're supposed to be the one
to finish this for me.
Do you know what it's like
reliving all the memories
of my dad
beating me up all the time?
Now I got a kid.
I can't even keep him well.
A kid that I have to hurt
over and over again every day,
including now,
killing his dream.
Just to keep him safe.
You don't get to tell me
about my life.
You will never understand
what I'm going through.
This never goes away
for me, man.
I have cancer, Bart.
It's one of those
really rare kinds, you know?
Like, no roadmap.
I mean, they operate
right when we get off tour,
and then it's chemo,
radiation, the whole thing.
It's got a lot of risks, too.
And what they're
saying is, um...
It isn't good.
And the timing really sucks
because I just
found out, uh...
I'm gonna be a dad.
Yep.
Hilary is pregnant.
She just told me.
And...
I mean, to be honest,
man, I'm...
I'm terrified.
And I'm angry
and sad that I might miss out
on a life
with the two of them.
I mean, I see you
with Sam and I...
That's my grief.
But this tour,
bucket list, bro.
I just wanna finish strong.
For Hilary, with Sam
and you and the guys.
And every moment
that I'm allowed to be here,
I just...
I wouldn't change it,
trade it in for the world.
My gratitude.
I'm finding a way
to hold them both...
together.
God is in fire, bro.
And it is beautiful.
(SNIFFLES)
Um...
You know, uh,
give it a listen.
If you hate it, uh,
I don't know, just trash it,
burn it, destroy it.
Doesn't really matter. Um...
If there's something there.
Now I feel like an idiot.
Listen to the friggin' song.
(MELANCHOLY MUSIC PLAYING)
BART: Did you know...
Tim was sick?
He asked me not to tell anyone
'cause he didn't
wanna be a distraction.
I guess I shouldn't have
let him swear me to secrecy.
I'm sorry about that.
Dad, Mary-Clair cut her arm.
Is it spraying?
No.
If it ain't spraying,
keep playing.
Tell her to rub some dirt
on it.
Sorry, Bart. Family day.
GIRL: Well, hurry up!
We're burning daylight!
BRICK: Okay.
(COUGHS)
Look, Brick.
I don't know, man.
Things are real bad
with Sam right now.
If I'm not home
keeping him on schedule...
I think I gotta quit.
BRICK: Hmm.
So I guess
this is the part
where I'm supposed to tell you
not to quit.
"Sometimes
those earth shattering moments
"in life,
"when your dreams vaporize
and die
"right before your eyes,
"it's then you realize
"that what you've been
searching for
"has been under your nose
all along."
Quitting's not gonna
solve your problems, Bart.
You obviously never read that.
Did I ever tell you
that my father went to prison?
No?
Yeah.
My dad goes away for two years
and overnight my entire
high school era
was gone.
I'd go see him in prison
every couple of weeks
and he was so concerned
about making the farm work
that that's all
he talked about.
"We can't lose
the farm, Scotty."
It became our whole deal.
(INHALES)
When all I really needed...
(SIGHS) was a dad.
And life handed you and Sam
something similar.
You just needed
to keep your son alive
and that became
your entire relationship.
But he needs more
than that from you.
Trust me.
Did you make it right
with you and your dad?
He's my best friend
in the world.
ARTHUR: Dreams don't pay
the bills.
All it does is keep you
from knowing what's real.
I wanna make things right
with you and me.
I don't know what to say.
I don't know how to do it.
I'm trying.
If God can forgive
everybody else,
why can't He forgive me?
BART: Dad, are you dying?
ARTHUR: Yeah.
Just do it.
BART: Hey. Hey, hey,
the doc said you're supposed
to take it easy.
Yeah, well, "Doc",
I'll sleep
when I'm dead.
I channeled
my inner Bart today.
I saw these
on the side of the road.
Couldn't let
the trash man get 'em.
Ah. Feast your eyes.
Oh!
Wow. Those...
are awful.
Beauty is in the eye
of the beholder.
I like 'em.
I love 'em.
-Here, help me out with this.
-Yeah.
All right.
You know,
I think people throw
things away for a reason.
ARTHUR: Some people
are stupid.
(PLAYING ACOUSTIC GUITAR)
That's sounding good.
You know, when I'm gone...
-Hey, I don't...
-...I want...
-Don't. I don't...
-No. No. Listen to me. Listen.
I want you to give this guitar
to somebody who can use it.
There's nothing worse
than a guitar
that's just laying around.
That's sadder
than a boat in the desert.
Ah, you're right.
These chairs are...
-butt-ugly.
-(CHUCKLES)
I don't know
what I was thinking.
BART: Neither do I.
I thought
all my dreams were dead.
My whole life, I dreamed...
of this.
Somethin' good.
With my dad.
And here we are.
Here we are.
Sometimes your dreams can...
Rise from the ashes.
Hi, I'm Bart.
Bart Millard.
First time I've ever
been to anything like this.
My wife thought
it would be a good idea
for me to come to one of these.
My relationship with my father
was complicated,
and now I have
a son of my own,
so I guess
that's why I'm here,
to fight for my son.
MAN: Welcome, Bart.
You'll fit right in here.
Thanks for sharing.
This is a safe place
to process those things
that we can't get past.
Does anyone else have
something they'd like to share
with the group?
Hey.
So...
Twenty questions, yeah?
Twenty questions.
-Twenty questions.
-Looks like it.
What's your favorite color?
Brick red.
You?
Uh,
like, a salmon kinda...
-Favorite book?
-Um...
Tim's Horatio book.
-It Is Well.
-Mmm.
Yeah. It was really good.
I got to read it
for a little while.
Hmm. Never learned
how to read.
So I'm gonna go
with Green Eggs and Ham.
-Oh.
-Favorite sport?
Wait, I know.
Football.
If we're talking
about real football
like soccer, then, yeah.
Ugh. Okay.
Oh, this is a good one.
One thing that's never
happened to me
that has happened to most?
Well, you're gonna
think it's stupid.
No, come on.
I've never seen
a shooting star.
You've never seen
a shooting star?
Bro, we gotta get you
outside more,
-okay?
-(CHUCKLES)
Feel like that's on me.
Never seen
a shooting star. Okay.
SAM: Um...
Thanks for setting this up.
I know we've been kinda...
Wait, I...
You didn't set...
-No.
-I thought you sent the...
No, I didn't.
That's okay. Um...
Yeah, it's fine.
-BART: Um...
-It's fine. I just...
I'm starting
to get a little tired,
so I think I'm just gonna go.
Well, I mean, maybe we could
pick this up another time,
you know?
You can go.
I mean, I want you there.
On the tour.
You can go.
MIKE: Come on, Bart, let's go.
NATHAN: Let's go, Bart.
BARRY: Let's go, Bart.
BRICK: We're burning
daylight here.
Chop, chop. Come on.
Did you set me and Sam up...
with the 20 questions thing?
-I did.
-Mmm.
My counselor uses
20 questions a lot
to just get things going.
Just trying to help.
(CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
Keep fighting.
I will.
I mean...
I am.
I...
It's for you.
Um, don't...
Just...
-I gotta go.
-Okay.
(HOPEFUL MUSIC PLAYS)
SAM: Chex Mix.
Check, one, two, one, two.
AUDIO ENGINEER: All right,
Sam. That's good, man.
We're gonna run a song.
Where's Tim?
SAM: Uh...
I'm not too sure.
Um, hold on.
I'll be right back. Hold on.
(GROANS)
-(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
-SAM: Hey, Tim?
Tim, they're ready for us.
My bro, I'm not feeling
so great. Uh...
-Sound check without me?
-(SAM CHUCKLES)
Yeah. Uh, sorry,
I don't think you understand.
I've never done that before.
I know.
You're gonna be great, buddy.
You just go do it. Go do it.
Okay. Yeah, I'll try.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
(SIGHS)
Just do what he says.
Just do it.
(EXHALES)
SAM OVER MIC:
Tim couldn't make it.
So, yeah, here we go.
(PLAYING ACOUSTIC GUITAR)
♪ Whatever my lot
♪ Thou hast...
Okay.
♪ ...taught me to say
♪ It is well
♪ With my soul
♪ Oh, it is well
♪ It is well
♪ It is well, it is well
it is well, it is well
♪ With my soul
♪ Whatever my lot
♪ Thou hast taught me to say
♪ It is well
♪ With my soul ♪
(CLAPPING)
MIKE: Woo! Okay.
-(CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
-He's incredible.
-So good.
-Jeez.
Oh, my gosh.
-It's unbelievable.
-Yeah, man.
Does this run in the family?
MAN: Coming through.
(SIGHS)
(CREAKING AND RATTLING)
(THUDS)
(BRAKES SQUEAKING)
BARRY: Nothing like
a good bus breakdown, huh?
NATHAN: I was having
the most amazing dream.
BARRY: Welcome to the road.
MIKE: Yeah.
What's up?
Radiator.
TIM: Okay. Okay, hold it.
Okay, okay.
Weirdest phobias.
Oh, well, Nathan's gotta
have the weirdest.
Oh, 100%.
It's cantilevered toilets.
What? What even is that?
I'm serious. They're the ones
where the thing, it just
sticks out from the wall
and there's nothing
underneath it to hold it up.
It's like it's floating there.
I don't trust it.
I don't like it.
-MIKE: I actually get that.
-Nathan, you're an alien.
-ROBBY: Bizarre.
-(GUYS LAUGHING)
Piranhas, the movie
at the cinema, 1978.
So how old are you?
(BAND MEMBERS LAUGHING)
NATHAN: Nice.
MIKE: Thanks.
No.
Sam,
-you're up.
-No. No.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah, go on.
-No, I...
-Come on.
-Come on, Sam.
-Go ahead.
-Um...
Needles.
TIM: Yeah, but you've been
around needles, like,
your whole life, man.
I'm sure that must
have been hard for you.
It is what it is.
You know, sometimes
the best way
to face your fears is...
Is with friends.
(GUYS LAUGH)
(CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
NATHAN: Are we doing this?
BART: Okay.
-Three, two...
-Two...
-Do the thumb.
-...one.
-(LANCETS CLICKING)
-(BARRY YELPS)
(ALL GROANING)
Bunch of lightweights.
That was a good one.
-(ALL GROANING)
-(LAUGHING)
SAM: Do you know
how many times I've done this?
-BART: Come on.
-(ROBBY GROANING)
Blood brothers!
(BART LAUGHING)
What say ye?
MIKE: Um...
-I'm in.
-MIKE: Yeah!
-Yeah. Why not?
-Let's get weird.
-Okay.
-Dude.
-This can't be safe.
-All right.
-Come on. Come on, man.
-All right. Coming.
I'm coming.
Guys, come on.
You're as much a part of this
as anybody. Let's go.
You first. Go ahead.
-Come on, Sammy.
-Come on, Sam.
-Yeah!
-Bring it in.
-Yeah! Sammy.
-Come on, Sammy, get in here.
-Yeah, let's go.
-(MIKE LAUGHS)
-Okay.
-Yeah.
And now we all have hepatitis.
(ALL CHEERING AND LAUGHING)
-That was great. Thanks.
-BART: Nice job, guys.
Favorite food?
Hit me
with that In-N-Out Burger.
Double-Double, animal style.
Fries.
Neapolitan shake.
Call it a night.
Um...
Favorite season?
Summer.
Cool.
Why?
The shots are always worse
in the cold.
So...
you know, summer helped.
I got you.
Let me see, seasons.
I gotta say spring.
You know?
Everything gets a redo.
Yeah.
Redos are good.
What was your favorite moment
with your dad?
It was his last day,
and he told me
he was proud of me
and that he loved me.
Only time.
It was...
everything.
You?
I'm sorry, son.
I'm trying.
I know.
I mean, all my life,
me and my dad, we had...
a complicated relationship,
to say the least.
I never wanted
to be that to you.
But then stuff happens
and then...
you find brand new ways
to hurt your son
and somehow you find yourself
back in the same chair.
In the end,
me and my dad, we...
We were... We were good.
I hope that
for me and you, too.
Every day.
(40 BY U2 PLAYING)
BART: Whoa,
are you seeing this?
SAM: (CHUCKLES)
What? That is awesome!
(HOWLING)
(SAM HOWLING)
Whoo!
♪ How long
♪ To sing this song
♪ I will sing
sing a new song
sing a new song ♪
Thank you.
Bart, get up, get up, get up.
We can't get him to wake up!
Come on!
BART: Sam! Sam.
SAM: Please wake up!
NATHAN: Hey, Tim, Tim.
Dad, I don't know
what happened.
-He just collapsed.
-Hey, it's okay. It's okay.
-Um, is he breathing?
-What do we do?
MIKE: Brick,
you gotta get 'em here quick.
Yeah, we just...
we're north bound.
We just passed
mile marker 367.
We need you to hurry.
(SAM SNIFFLES)
BRICK: Please hurry.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I asked the staff if I could,
like, push a button,
make the heart monitor
do that flatline thingie,
like, right
when you walked in.
They told me
it'd be in poor taste.
It's funny, though, right?
It's pretty funny.
Yeah, they gave me
something to sleep.
I don't know
how much longer I'll...
(SNORING SOFTLY)
(SNORTS) I'm messing with you.
(TIM CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
But they did
give me something.
Boy, it's really coming down.
The...
doctors (INHALES)
told me
I can't finish the tour.
They're gonna have to operate
a little sooner
than they hoped.
I'm sorry, man.
No, I'm sorry.
I feel like I'm letting
you guys down.
I really wanted to finish this.
Ah, man, don't say that.
Wow.
Wow, the things
I may never finish, wow.
Hey, speaking of,
how's our song coming along?
Like, I got through the chorus
and the bridge.
I just... I got tripped up
on the verses.
I know it wouldn't take
much to finish...
I haven't listened to it, man.
I'm sorry.
Well, that hurts
my feelings a little.
Um...
I guess...
sometimes you win some,
sometimes you lose some.
Whoa, drugs are
really kicking in right now.
I don't think you're gonna
have to suffer this fool
much longer.
I don't know.
Feel like I could suffer him
a little longer.
That's outta character
for you.
I'm flattered.
Now there's
one beautiful thing...
suffering does.
It teaches you empathy.
In my song,
God is in the fire.
That's funny.
Oh, I can see it now.
God is in the storm, too.
Maybe God's in everything.
Wouldn't that be...
(HOPEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
TIM: I've always been obsessed
with It Is Well With My Soul.
One of the hardest
redemption stories
I've ever heard
which led to one
of the greatest hymns
of all time.
I'd love to write a song
like that someday.
TIM ON CD: So, Bart,
if you're listening to this,
I'm probably dead?
(CHUCKLES)
I'm kidding, I'm kidding.
No, no, it was a joke.
That was just a great joke.
Um, yeah, okay.
So, here we go.
(PLAYING ACOUSTIC GUITAR)
TIM: I guess...
sometimes you win some
and sometimes you lose some.
BART: I think God gave
our kid the wrong dad.
Like, I'm the wrong one.
Man, why does life
have to be so hard? Why...
Why don't you show up
face to face for us when
everything goes dark?
TIM: My grief and my gratitude.
I'm trying to find a way
to hold them both...
together.
In my song,
God is in the fire.
God is in the storm, too.
BART ON VOICEMAIL:
Shannon, hey, it's me. Um...
Just checking in. I...
Hilary's still at the hospital
with Tim and...
It's... It's not looking good.
He wanted me to work
on this song for him.
I finished it last night
and I...
I don't know, something
about it feels different.
I haven't really gotten
this feeling about a song
in a long time. Just...
Excited to share it with you.
Our final show at Red Rocks
is at the end of the week.
Man, I wish you guys could
be there with me.
I miss you
and the kids.
I think things
are gonna be different.
I've been fighting.
I've been really fighting.
I love you, Millard.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ To sing this song ♪
(CROWD CHEERING)
You having a good time?
Whoo!
Man, what a crowd. Um...
This is our final stop.
It's been
an unforgettable tour. Um...
It got us thinking
if we could...
If we could sing
just one last song for you,
before this thing was over,
what would we sing?
So, uh...
This is it.
(CROWD CHEERING
AND CLAPPING)
(EXHALES)
(SOFTLY) I think
we gotta bring Sam in.
-Absolutely. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-Come on.
-Talk to the guy.
-Okay.
BART: Hey, Sam.
What are we doing?
You wanna play with us?
-Come on.
-Sam is joining.
BART: He's coming for you.
Get ready.
SAM: Okay.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(CROWD CLAPPING)
BART: I... I have to do this.
This is my son.
(CROWD CHEERING)
BART: (CHUCKLES) Yeah, yeah.
This is my son and...
We've been through a lot.
This last song was written
by our dear friend,
Tim Timmons.
He's...
He's real sick right now.
But he graciously let me
finish this one with him
and...
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Tim couldn't be here tonight
but he always gives
a powerful gift to the world
and the same powerful gift
that he gave me,
gratitude.
Unflinching gratitude.
There's so much beauty
in the world and...
in it...
Shannon?
(CHUCKLING SOFTLY)
Ladies and gentlemen,
my beautiful wife,
Shannon is here tonight.
Give it up for Shannon.
What are you doing here, babe?
And is that Tim
and Hilary, too?
Okay. I don't know
what's going on right now.
Ladies and gentlemen,
my man, Tim Timmons
is in the house right now
with his wife.
Give it up for them. Come on.
I thought you were
in the hospital, man.
(CHUCKLING)
What are you doing here?
This one's for Tim.
♪ They say
sometimes you win some
♪ Sometimes you lose some
♪ Right now
♪ Right now I'm losing bad
♪ Stood on this stage
♪ Night after night
♪ Reminding the broken
it'll be all right
♪ But right now
♪ Oh, right now I just can't
♪ It's easy to sing
♪ When there's nothing
to bring me down
♪ What will I say
♪ When I'm held to the flame
♪ Like I am right now
♪ I know You're able
and I know You can
♪ Save through the fire
with Your mighty hand
♪ But even if You don't
♪ My hope is You alone
♪ They say
it only takes a little faith
♪ To move a mountain
♪ Good thing
♪ 'Cause little faith is
all I have right now
♪ God, when You choose
♪ To leave
mountains unmovable
♪ Oh, give me the strength
to be able to sing
♪ It is well with my soul
♪ I know You're able
and I know You can
♪ Save through the fire
with Your mighty hand
♪ But even if You don't
♪ My hope is You alone
♪ I know the sorrow
and I know the hurt
♪ Would all go away
if You'd just say the word
-♪ But even if You don't
-♪ Even if You don't
♪ My hope is You alone
♪ You've been faithful
♪ You've been good
♪ All of my days
♪ Jesus, I will cling to You
♪ Come what may
♪ 'Cause I know You're able
♪ I know You can
♪ I know You're able
♪ And I know You can
♪ Save through the fire
with Your mighty hand
♪ But even if You don't
♪ My hope is You alone
♪ I know the sorrow
♪ I know the hurt
♪ Would all go away
if You'd just say the word
♪ But even if You don't
♪ My hope is You alone
(VOCALIZING)
♪ It is well
♪ With my soul
♪ It is well with
♪ My soul ♪
Whoo!
Wow!
(CROWD CHEERING)
I'm so proud of you.
I've always been proud of you.
You're the best part
of me, son.
(OUTRO BY M83 PLAYING)
♪ I'm the king
of my own land
All right, Tim, Shannon,
I'm coming for you.
♪ I'll fight until the end ♪
You did it, man.
Horatio's soul.
My soul, man?
No, Tim.
You don't even see it, do you?
It's you.
The song is you.
Thank you for showing me
the way back.
Your X is crooked.
Yean, man. You gotta learn
how to draw straight lines,
you weirdo.
Go get the girl, bro.
I'm back, Millard.
I'm back.
No.
You're home.
BART: "I found a song
"that opened my life
up to things
"I could never have
possibly imagined.
"A hard song, of loss,
heartbreak, grief,
"and yet a song
that made me believe
"dreams do come true."
"Through the ages,
as artists of faith,
"we search for the sacred,
"the eternal.
"We sing of the things
that last
"and stand the test of time,
"always looking
for the strength
"and the truth
to be able to say,
"'It is well with my soul.'
"Sometimes all we can do is
look to Heaven
"past all the
happily-ever-afters
"that may never come,
"all of the unanswered
questions, and just say
"'No matter what,
I trust You.'
"Because in the end,
"we're all just a small part
of an eternal story.
"The story
of the goodness of God."
"What do you do
"when the only thing
in the world you have
"to hang on to is a song?"
You keep holding on.
(ON OUR WAY
BY SAM WESLEY PLAYING)
♪ Yeah, we're on our way
-♪ Oh, oh, oh
-♪ We're on our way
♪ We're on our way
to breaking through'
♪ 'Cause we were made
for something new
♪ We're on our way
to chase our dreams
♪ 'Cause we were made
for greater things
♪ Yeah, we're on our way
♪ Here's to all the scared
and frozen
♪ Too afraid
of the unknown and
♪ Second-guessing
everything you once believed
♪ There's no fear
that can bind you
♪ There's nowhere
hope won't find you
♪ As long as we have hope
♪ We have everything we need
♪ Yeah, we're on our way
♪ We're on our way
to breaking through
♪ 'Cause we were made
for something new
♪ Yeah, we're on our way
♪ We're on our way
to chase our dreams
♪ 'Cause we were made
for greater things
♪ Yeah, we're on our way
-♪ In this moment
-♪ It's electric
♪ Can you see it?
Can you feel it?
♪ This dream inside
is still alive
♪ We're on our way
to breaking through
♪ 'Cause we were made
for something new
♪ Yeah, we're on our way
♪ We have everything we need
♪ We're on our way
♪ Yeah, we're on our way ♪
BRICK: Say, Dad,
do you ever wanna talk
about your feelings?
Not really.
Yeah, me neither.
Thanks for the...
For the book.
(MAKE IT WELL
BY MERCYME PLAYING)
♪ Make it well
♪ With my soul
♪ Don't let me face
this loneliness alone
♪ Make it well
♪ With my soul
♪ I need a peace
that only heaven knows
♪ Jesus could you please
♪ Just sit and cry with me
♪ Till I can sing
♪ It is well with my soul
♪ Whatever my lot
♪ You are still my God
♪ It is well, it is well
with my soul
♪ Make it well
♪ With my soul
♪ When the storm is raging
please don't let me go
♪ Oh, voice
that calms the sea
♪ Keep whispering to me
♪ So I can sing
♪ It is well with my soul
♪ Whatever my lot
♪ You are still my God
♪ It is well
♪ It is well with my soul
♪ Make it well with my soul
(VOCALIZING)
♪ Make it well
♪ With my soul
♪ Keep this heart
from hardening like stone
♪ Show me through the pain
♪ There's reason
still to praise
♪ So I can sing
♪ It is well with my soul
♪ Whatever my lot
You are still my God
♪ Oh, whatever my lot
♪ You are still my God
♪ It is well
♪ It is well with my soul ♪
(MUSIC ENDS)
MAN: In another section,
I was thinking...
(EVEN IF PLAYING)
(VOCALIZING)
♪ Oh, I know You're able
and I know You can
♪ Save through the fire
with Your mighty hand
♪ But even if You don't
♪ My hope is You alone
♪ 'Cause I choose to follow
and I choose to stand
♪ Come hell or high water
You'll rest in the plan
♪ But through
the rain I know
♪ My hope is you alone ♪